Hi, in this lesson you will learn how to upload files into chat GPT and use them as a part
of your context when working on for instance coding tasks.
You understand what kind of files you can add, how chat GPT uses them, and how it helps
to analyze and debug your code faster.
So let's talk about file uploading.
When you open new chat, you will see the small icon plus when you click on it, you will
be able to add photos of files.
So, you can upload any files like text files, some code files, even PDF files from documentation,
chat GPT, we will accept them and read.
Okay, let's, I prepared some type of files from preact application, as examples, deal
work with them.
So, let's first upload the package.json files with all libraries of a project contained.
So, once you upload the files, chat GPT automatically reads this file and add it as a context
add to a chat.
That means you don't have to copy paste your file anymore, chat GPT will remember it and
will already have access to all the context in this file.
So, let's ask something about this file.
For example, what libraries is used in this application?
Oops, sorry, what?
And let's see how GPT is working with the files.
So, at least the file is libraries we use right here in dependencies like React, React DOM,
Excels, and other lips, you also leave the files as developer dependencies, and as you see,
you can easily work with the files and read all the context, so it doesn't matter, it
code files or PDF, so it works same.
Okay, let's now talk about the context and what it is.
Context is simply the information chat GPT uses to understand your request.
When you upload the file, it becomes part of the conversation context, just like you
previous messages in this chat.
So, if you ask GPT, can you find the bug in this file or can you refactor this function?
Oh, question, we ask what libraries is used here.
He looks directly at all you uploaded files in this conversation and you generate answers
to you.
The context stays active for a slow on your chat is open, so if you can continue, do some
refactoring or do some changes in this file.
In part of the moment, when you switch to another chat, your context is also switched.
So, GPT, remember all things you upload will tell him only in the context of one conversation.
It's really important to understand.
Okay, so we can ask the follow-up questions about the files.
For example, I can ask a great React version to select this one.
First of all, ask what version we use, what React version, do I use to use in React 19.
I'm not sure, I'm using React 19, so let's quickly check, yeah, I'm using React 19.
Okay.
And it won't work, I might be, what is the latest one?
I think I've already upgraded the newer version, so I can ask, please upgrade to the newer
version.
Please upgrade to this one.
And you see, he'll send you the updated package, the JSON file, so with a new version, so
we can just copy paste it and save, and then he'll suggest you the command, how we can upgrade
it.
We can also need to upgrade the library, so we can really work fine with context, but can
it work with multiple files? And answer is yes, you can upload the more files and one like
two, three, five files, of course, GPT has some limitations.
I don't remember how much profiles but for photos, it's about eight or 10 photos, so I guess
profiles might be same.
And for example, if you upload few files, it also will be added to your context, and you
can ask follow-up questions about these files as well.
Let's upload IAP and loader j6 files, and let's ask something, so what difference between
these components?
What difference between those components?
Okay, you see, as quickly read all the files, he says the application is the main component
in your application and the loader is small visual component.
It just shows the loading spinner animation, but the main container displays a form, a
load, and loader, so you see it give you an explanation.
Okay, also, JGPT has some limitations.
So as a quick note, JGPT doesn't parameter the story of files, as they exist on the inside
of your current chat.
Once you delete your chat, you start in U1, your files are gone.
So if you want to continue working later, just request those files.
So if you create a new file, you delete the chat, you can report your files later.
But I recommend you to stay, if you already uploaded files, don't delete this chat, and
just continue your follow-up questions on the next day in a week later, so you can ask
it.
So, complex is not infinity.
JGPT has the memory limit per chat.
It can only keep a certain amount of information active at once.
It's logical, yeah, because you cannot, you know, paste a thousand messages and thousand
files and JGPT, you need a lot of resources for it, so especially if you use the free version,
your contacts will be limited in paid accounts, it can be bigger, but a limited same.
And if a chat gets pulled on or files very large, like other parts of the conversation may
start to be paid from memory.
That means the JGPT, my stop remember is some information you are sent to them, you'll
miss some connections between big files to avoid the situation, I suggest you keep your uploaded
files small and focused, so if you work on a large project, please don't upload the whole
project folder to JGPT, keep the file file small and relevant, so just upload the relevant
files and ask an answer.
Try to focus on files related to the questions, and JGPT will provide you more accurate
results and we will remember all the things, as he can.
Let's wrap up the lesson, so now you know how to upload files, how is JGPT using them
as the contacts and how to manage multiple files in your coding sessions, so after the
lesson you can confidently bring your own code in the JGPT and let the AI to analyze the
bug and improve your introductory files faster, okay, see you in the next lesson.